To get away clean, you have to play dirty.
Parker is a action, crime film directed by Taylor Hackford.
A thief with a unique code of professional ethics is
double-crossed by his crew and left for dead.
Assuming a new disguise and forming an unlikely alliance with a woman on the
inside, he looks to hijack the score of the crew's latest heist.
Parker, played by Jason Statham.
Leslie Rodgers, played by Jennifer Lopez.
Melander, played by Michael Chiklis.
Carlson, played by Wendell Pierce.
Ross, played by Clifton Collins Jr..
Jake Fernandez, played by Bobby Cannavale.
Parker is a 2013 American action thriller film directed
by Taylor Hackford and written by John J.
McLaughlin.
Starring Jason Statham and Jennifer Lopez, the film is adapted from Flashfire, the 19th
Parker novel written by Donald Westlake under the pen name Richard Stark.
Primarily set in Palm Beach, Florida, Parker marked a departure for
Hackford, who hoped to make it his first film noir.
The film, produced on a $35 million budget, was conceived following Westlake's
2008 death, when producer Les Alexander secured the rights to it.
The film was premiered in Las Vegas, Nevada, on January 24, 2013, and was released in the United States on January 25, 2013, where it generally received mixed
reviews, with many critics feeling the film was a poor adaptation of the book and typical of Statham's sub-par action films of the past few years.
Many found Statham well-fitted for the role of Parker and
praised Lopez for providing comedic relief.
It grossed $46 million worldwide at the box office.
Parker premiered on Netflix in the United States in March 2021, and a week
later was briefly the #1 film on the streaming service.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, real estate agent,
professional thief, jewel robbery, palm beach, florida.